<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Ar[c?]ticles to be inquired of, in the visitation of the most reverend father in God, Richard, by the providence of God, Lord Arch-bishop of Yorke, primate of England, and metropolitane had in the yeere of our Lord God 1636.</title>
            <author>Church of England. Province of York. Archbishop (1631-1640 : Neile)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1636</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A00272</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 10380.5</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S2656</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">24456557</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 24456557</idno>
            <idno type="VID">27689</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A00272)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 27689)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1851:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Ar[c?]ticles to be inquired of, in the visitation of the most reverend father in God, Richard, by the providence of God, Lord Arch-bishop of Yorke, primate of England, and metropolitane had in the yeere of our Lord God 1636.</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Province of York. Archbishop (1631-1640 : Neile)</author>
                  <author>Neile, Richard, 1562-1640.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by John Norton,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1636.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: A-B⁴.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
               <term>Visitations, Ecclesiastical --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:27689:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:27689:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>ARCTICLES TO BE INQVI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>RED OF, IN THE VISITATION OF the moſt Reverend Father in <hi>God,</hi> RICHARD, <hi>by the Providence of GOD,</hi> Lord Arch-biſhop of <hi>York<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate of</hi> England, <hi>and Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tropolitane.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Had in the Yeere of our Lord <hi>God,</hi> 1636.</p>
            <p>LONDON Printed by JOHN NOR<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>TON. 1636.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="notice">
            <pb facs="tcp:27689:2"/>
            <head>The Advertiſem<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nt.</head>
            <p>THe Miniſter, and Church-wardens are to call unto them the Neyghboures of the Pariſh, and out of them to make choyce (according to the cuſtome of the place) of two of the diſcreeteſt pariſhioners to be Side-men, and they al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>together are to reade over theſe Articles divers times. Then, after they have duely conſidered of them, they are to write their anſwere or preſentment unto every Article particularly, and truely, according to their conſciences. Laſtly, they are all of them to bring their preſentments to the Viſitation, and there the Church-wardens, and Side-men upon their oathes (but the Minister according to the Canon in that behalfe) are to deliver them up under their handes.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="oath_of_churchwardens_and_sworn_men">
            <head>The oath to bee miniſtred to the Church-wardens, &amp; Sworne men.</head>
            <p>YOu ſhall ſweare, that all affection, favour, hatred, hope of reward, and gaine, or feare of diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleaſure or malice ſet aſide: you ſhall upon due con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration of the Articles given you in charge, preſent all and every ſuch perſon of, or within your Pariſh, as hath committed any offence or fault, or made any default mentioned in theſe, or any of theſe Articles, or which are vehemently ſuſpected, and defamed of any ſuch offence, fault or default: wherein you ſhall deliver uprightly, and according to truth; neyther of malice preſenting any contrary to truth; nor of corrupt affection ſparing to preſent any, and ſo conceale the truth, having in this action God before your eyes with an earneſt zeale to mayntaine truth, &amp; to ſuppreſſe Vice; ſo helpe you God, and the contents of this Booke.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="articles_of_visitation">
            <pb facs="tcp:27689:2"/>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Touching the Church, Church-yard, Parſonage, and Vicarage-houſe</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Irſt, whether your Church, Chappell, and Chancell be well, and ſufficiently repaired in the walls, and roofe, the Seats conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent, the floore paved, the windowes glazed, your Bells in tune, and all theſe cleanely kept, and the manſion-houſe of your Parſon or Vicar, with the building thereunto be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing, be likewiſe well, and ſufficiently repayred, and your Church-yard well fenced with walls, rayles, or payles, and cleanely kept.</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether hath your Church or Church-yard beene abuſed, and prophaned by any fighting, chiding, brawling or quarrel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, any playes, Lords of miſrule, ſummer Lords, morris, dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, pedlers, bowlers, bearewards, butchers, feaſts, ſchooles, temporall courts, o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Leets, Lay Iuries, muſters, or other pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phane uſage in your Church or Church-yard, any hells ſuper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitiouſly rung on Holidayes or their eeves, or at any other time without good cauſe allowed by the Miniſter, and Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens: have any Trees beene felled in your Church-yard, and by whom?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether are your Almeſ-houſes, and Church-Houſe if you have any ſufficently repayred, mayntained, and to godly, and their right uſe imployed?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether have you in your Church all things neceſſary for common prayer, as the Bible in the largeſt volume, the books of common Prayer, the booke of <hi>Homilies</hi> allowed, two bookes of common Prayer, a convenient Pulpit for the preaching, a decent ſeat for the Miniſter to reade Service in, conveniently placed, a ſtrong cheſt, with three lockes and keyes, one for the Miniſter, the other for the Church-wardens for the keéping of the Regiſter booke of the Chriſtnings, Marriages, and Buri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als, and a poore mans boxe with three locks; conveniently placed neere the Church doore?</p>
               <p n="5">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27689:3"/> 5 Whether have you in your Church a font of ſtone for bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſme ſet in the ancient uſuall place: a decent table for the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion conveniently placed, covered with ſilke, or other decent ſtuffe in time of Divine Service, and with a faire linnen cloth over that, at the adminiſtration of the Communion?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether have you all ſuch bells, ornaments, and other uten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſils as have anciently belonged to your Church, a communion-cup of ſilver with a cover, a faire ſtanding pot or two of pewter or purer metall for the wine upon the communion table, a come<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Surpleſſe with ſleeves, a Regiſter booke of parchment, for chriſtnings, marriages, &amp; burials, a booke for the names of all ſtrange preachers, ſubſcribed with their names, and the name of the Biſhop, or other, by whom they had licenſe to preach.</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether is the <hi>Almes</hi> for the poore duely diſtributed, and are the names, &amp; ſurnames of all perſons married, chriſtened, and buried, and of their parents, with the day, and yeere entred in your parchment Regiſter booke?</p>
               <p n="8">8 Whether are y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ten Commandements ſet up in your Church or Chappell, and other choſen ſentences of holy Scripture up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the walls in convenient places, and the Table of the degrees prohibited in marriage, ſet forth 1563?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Whether have you in your Church or Chappell the booke of the <hi>Canons</hi> agreed upon in the convocation holden at <hi>London Anno. Dom. 1603.</hi> and confirmed by his Maieſties royall autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, and whether your Miniſter have read the ſame in your Church or Chappell once every yeere, according to his Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Iniunctions in that behalfe?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Touching the Miniſtery, Service, and Sacraments.</head>
               <p>VVHether is the common prayer ſaid or ſung by your Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter both morning, &amp; evening, diſtinctly, &amp; reverently every Sunday, and Holiday, and on their eeves, and at conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient and uſuall times of thoſe dayes, and in moſt convenient place of the Church for the edifying of the people?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether doth your Miniſter obſerve the orders, rites, &amp; ce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>remonies preſcribed in the booke of common prayer, in reading holy Scriptures, prayers, &amp; adminiſtration of the Sacraments
<pb facs="tcp:27689:3"/>without diminiſhing (in regard of preaching or any other re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect) or adding any thing in the manner or forme thereof?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether doth your Miniſter on wedneſdaies, and fridaies not being holidaies, at the accuſtomed houres of ſervice, reſort to the Church, and ſay the ordinary prayers, and Letany pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed? And doth your Clarke or Sexton give warning before by tolling of a bell on thoſe daies?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether any Miniſter leaving the uſe of the Font, doe in your Church or Chappell chriſten or baptize in any baſons, or other profane veſſells: or whether your Miniſter do baptize or chriſten any out of the face of the Church, &amp; Congregation with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out ſpeciall cauſe, or without Godfathers or Godmothers: And whether any perſon or perſons be admitted to anſwere as God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>father, &amp; Godmother at the chriſtening of any child, except he or ſh<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> have before received the holy Communion: and whether doth your Miniſter in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> baptizing of children, obſerve y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> orders rites, &amp; ceremonies appointed, &amp; preſcribed in the booke of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon prayer, without addition omiſſion or other innovation?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether doe you know any Parents that keepe children unchriſtened, or that were not chriſtened at their owne Pariſh Church or Chappell, &amp; for what cauſe they remaine yet unchri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtened, or have not beene chriſtened at their Pariſh Church or Chappell: or doe you know, have heard, or vehemently ſuſpect any parents, whoſe children have beene chriſtened by any Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſh Prieſt, or otherwiſe than by the lawes of the Church of <hi>England</hi> is allowed?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether doth your Miniſter as oft as he adminiſtreth the communion, firſt receive it himſelfe in both kinds, and whether doth he uſe in the adminiſtration any bread, and wine newly brought before it be ſet upon the Communion Table, and the words of conſecration be rehearſed, &amp; doth he deliver the bread, and wine to every communicant ſeverally in ſuch ſort as is preſcribed?</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether doth your Miniſter give warning publikely in the Church at Morning prayer y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Sunday before he adminiſtreth the communion for the better preparation of the pariſhioners? and whether doth he adminiſter the Sacraments ſo often as that every pariſhioner may receive thrice in the yeere at the leaſt, whereof <hi>Eaſter</hi> to be one?</p>
               <p n="8">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27689:4" rendition="simple:additions"/> 8 Whether hath your Miniſter adminiſtred the Communion to any but ſuch as kneele, or doe you know any that refuſe to kneele: hath he adminiſtred to any that are under <hi>Eccleſiaſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>call</hi> cenſure, as for refuſing to bee preſent at publike Prayer, or who hath depraved the booke of common Prayer, and adminiſtration of the Sacraments or the Rites, &amp; Cere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monies, preſcribed, or the Articles of Religion agreed upon, or the Booke of ordering <hi>Deacons<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Prieſts<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> &amp; <hi>Biſhops,</hi> or againſt his <hi>Majeſties</hi> Supremacy: or hath committed other the like en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ormities, and what be their names?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Whether hath your Miniſter more Benefices than one: if he have, how far diſtant are they, how often is he abſent in the yeere? when he is abſent from your parſonage or vicaradge, hath he a licenſed Preacher for his Curate?</p>
               <p n="10">10 Whether your Churches or Chappels be or have beene deſtitute of a Curate? And how long, and by whoſe default? And whether any Curate have ſerved, or doe ſerve without li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſe of the Ordinary? or doe any officiate in any cure that is not in holy orders.</p>
               <p n="11">11 Whether doe youknow any Popiſh <hi>Prieſts, Seminary, Jeſuite,</hi> or runnagate perſons, that doe preach, ſay Maſſe, or mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter any Popiſh Sacrament or ceremonies, or elſe doe reſort ſecretly or openly into your Pariſh: And whoſe houſe doe they reſort unto and of whom are they harboured, and what be the names of ſuch Popiſh <hi>Prieſts, Seminaries, Ieſuites,</hi> or Runna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gates<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and ſuch as ſo harbour and releeve them?</p>
               <p n="12">12 Whether your Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, or any other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon in your pariſh be a favourer of the <hi>Romiſh Church</hi> or Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion, or any other Sect or Schiſmaticall opinio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, or hath or doth maintaine or teach any doctrine contrary or repugnant to Gods Word or to any of the Articles agreed upon by the <hi>Clergy</hi> in the Convocation holden at <hi>London, An. Dom. 1562.</hi> And whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther they have taught publiquely or ſecretly any doctrine ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the diſcredit, and diſprayſe either of the Booke of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Prayer, or of the Preachers, and Miniſters of the Word, and Sacraments, or of the received order for government by <hi>Arch-biſhops, Biſhops, Deanes, Arch-deacons,</hi> and other offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers in the Church of <hi>England,</hi> or make any other innovati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> And whether have they permitted any man ſo teaching
<pb facs="tcp:27689:4"/>or making ſuch innovation, and not made the ſame knowne.</p>
               <p n="13">13 Whether is your Miniſter an allowed Preacher: if he be, doth he every Sunday in your Church or ſome other next ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ioyning, where no Preacher is, preach?</p>
               <p n="14">14 Whether doth your Miniſter being no Preacher allowed preſume to expound the Scripture in his owne Cure or elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where: doth he procure every month a Sermon to be preached in his cure by preachers lawfully licenced, and on every Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day when there is no Sermon, doth he or his Curate reade ſome one of the <hi>Homilies</hi> preſcribed?</p>
               <p n="15">15 Whether your Miniſter doe openly every Sunday after he have read the ſecond <hi>Leſſon</hi> at Morning &amp; Evening praier, ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moniſh &amp; warne the Church-wardens, &amp; Sworne men to looke to their charge, &amp; to obſerve who offend in abſenting themſelves negligently or wilfully from their Pariſh-church or Chappell, or unreverently uſe themſelves in time of divine Service?</p>
               <p n="16">16 Whether is your Curate allowed by the Ordinary under his hand, &amp; ſeale to ſerve for your cure, and whether doth he ſerve two Churches or Chappells in one day? whether is he <hi>Dea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>con</hi> at the leaſt, &amp; what ſtipend hath he for ſerving the cure?</p>
               <p n="17">17 Whether doth your Miniſter alwaies in ſaying publike prayer, &amp; adminiſtring the Sacraments, weare a decent ſurpleſſe with ſleeves &amp; being a graduate, doth he alwayes weare there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with a hood by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> order of the <hi>Vniverſity,</hi> agreeable to his degree?</p>
               <p n="18">18 Whether hath your Miniſter or any other Preacher in your church, preached any thing to confute or impugne any do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine delivered by any other Preacher, &amp; hath he, &amp; they prayed for <hi>Chriſts Catholike Church,</hi> the <hi>Kings Majeſty,</hi> the <hi>Lords Arch-biſhops,</hi> and <hi>Biſhops,</hi> &amp;c. as is preſcribed, <hi>Canon 55.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="19">19 Whether hath or doth any preach in your Church, which re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſeth to conforme himſelfe to the Lawes, Rites, &amp; Ordinances eſtabliſhed, or which hath not firſt ſhewed a ſufficient licenſe.</p>
               <p n="20">20 Whether doth your Miniſter in his ſermons foure times in the yeere at the leaſt, teach, and declare the <hi>Kings Majeſties</hi> power within his realmes to be the higheſt power under God, to whom all within the ſame owe moſt loyalty, and obedience, and that all forraine power is iuſtly aboliſhed?</p>
               <p n="21">21 Whether doth your Miniſter every Sunday, and Holiday
<pb facs="tcp:27689:5"/>halfe an houre before Eevening prayer or more, or at ſome other convenient time at Eevening prayer examine, and inſtruct the youth in the ten Commandements, the Beleefe, the Lords Prayer, &amp; the Catechiſme, ſet forth in the Booke of Common prayer, and whether doe the Church-wardens aſſiſt the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter herein?</p>
               <p n="22">22 Whether hath your Miniſter married any which have not beene three ſeverall Sundaies or Holydaies asked in your Church in the time of divine ſervice, without licence or without a ring: or hath he with licence or without, married any, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of neyther dwelt in your Pariſh?</p>
               <p n="23">23 Whether hath your Miniſter with licence or without, married any, at any other times than betweene the houres of eight, and twelve in the Forenoone, or in any private houſe, or when there is no licence, before the Parents, and Governours (the parties being under the age of 22. yeeres) have teſtified their conſents?</p>
               <p n="24">24 Whether hath your Miniſter declared to the people every Sunday at the time appointed, what Holidaies, and Faſting<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daies be that weeke following: doth he being a Preacher confer with all recuſants, and perſons excommunicate or ſuſpended? being no Preacher doth he procure a ſufficient Preacher to reclaime them thereby?</p>
               <p n="25">25 Whether doth your Miniſter keepe a note of all perſons excommunicated, and declared ſo to be, and once every ſixe moneths doth he denounce them which have not obtained their abſolution on ſome Sunday in ſervice time, that others may be admoniſhed to refraine their company?</p>
               <p n="26">26 Whether your Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, be diligent in diſiting the ſicke, and comforting them, and whether they bury their dead in ſuch chriſtian, and comely manner as is preſcribed in the Booke of Common prayer, and whether any Lay man, other than a lawfull Miniſter, hath taken upon him to bury the dead contrary to Order?</p>
               <p n="27">27 Whether hath your Miniſter refuſed to baptize any childe brought to the Church, or to bury any corps brought into the Church or Church-yard, or to Church any woman, having had convenient warning thereof?</p>
               <p n="28">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27689:5"/> 28 Whether hath your Miniſter being truely informed of the danger of death of any infant vnbaptized, and being deſtred to go to the place where the child is, to baptize it, neglected to go, by meanes whereof the child hath dyed unbaptized?</p>
               <p n="29">29 Whether doth your Miniſter at any time preach or admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter the Communion in any private Houſe except when they are ſo impotent that they cannot goe to Church; or very danger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly ſicke?</p>
               <p n="30">30 Whether doe any Chaplens in your Pariſh, preach, or admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter the Sacrament in any Chappell not conſecrated, or in any Houſe having no Chappell allowed by Law, and doe the Lords, and Maſters where ſuch Chappels are, reſort often to the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh-church, and there receive the Communion once at the leaſt every yeere?</p>
               <p n="31">31 Whether hath your Miniſter held or appointed any pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like faſt not appointed by Authority, or beone preſent at ſuch: doth he or any other in your Pariſh hold any lecture or exerciſe, or attempt by Faſting, or Prayer, or otherwiſe, to caſt out any Devils, without the privity, and allowance of the <hi>Biſhop</hi> under his Hand, and Seale?</p>
               <p n="32">32 Whether hath there beene any ſecret Conventicles or mee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings in your Pariſh by any Prieſts. Miniſters, or others, ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the depraving of the forme of Prayer, Doctrins or Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment of the Church?</p>
               <p n="33">33 Whether doth your Miniſter weare decent apparell, doth he in publike goe in his Doublet, and Hoſe, without a Coate, or Caſſocke, or Cloake, and doth he weare any unſeemely, and light<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coloured apparell?</p>
               <p n="34">34 Whether doth your Miniſter make accuſtomed reſort to: any <hi>Taverns,</hi> or <hi>Ale-houſes,</hi> except for his honeſt neceſſities or doth he boord or lodge in any ſuch place, doth he uſe any baſe or ſervile labour, or frequent drinking, riot, dice, cards, tables, or any other vnlawfull games: is he contentious with his neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, or a Hunter, Hanker<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſwearer, dancer, uſurer ſuſpected of incontinency, or doth give evill example of life?</p>
               <p n="35">35 Whether is there in your Pariſh any Miniſter or Deacon who hath forſaken his calling, uſing himſelfe in his courſe of life as a meere Lay man.</p>
               <p n="36">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27689:6"/> 36 Whether is his <hi>Majeſties</hi> declaration lately publiſhed for quieting, and ſilencing the controverſies lately ſtirred up to the diſturbance of our Church with new queſtions, ſtrictly obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved by your Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, or whomſoever elſe that preacheth in your Church?</p>
               <p n="37">37 Whether doth your Parſon, Vicar, Curate or Lecturer, catechize the youth of the Pariſh in your Church, every Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day after dinner by queſtion, and anſwere; and apply his after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noone preaching, and exhortation, to the inſtructing, and edifying of the congregation in that kind of catechizing if he Preach?</p>
               <p n="38">38 Whether have you in your Pariſh any weeke-day Lecture, or not? And if you have, by whom is the ſame performed; whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther by one particular man thereto licenſed, or by ſundry neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour Miniſters, and whether are the publike prayers alwaies read, before ſuch lecture, and ſermons, in his ſurpleſſe, and hood, according to his <hi>Majeſties</hi> inſtructions lately ſet forth?</p>
               <p n="39">39 Whether are there any within your Pariſh (under the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree of Noblemen, and men qualified by Law) who doe keepe any private Chaplaines in their Houſes?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Touching Eccleſiaſticall Courts.</head>
               <p>FIrſt, whether the Chancellor, Commiſſaries, or any other uſing Eccleſiaſticall Iuriſdiction in this Dioceſſe, their Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſters, or Actuaries, Apparitors or Sumners, have at any time beene corrupt in their places, or taken any exceſſive fees, or win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked at, &amp; ſuffred any Adulteries, Fornications, Inceſts, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther faults, or offences to paſſe, &amp; remaine unpuniſhed, and uncor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected, or have commuted any penance without ſpeciall licence of the <hi>Biſhop?</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether doe you know that there hath beene any commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation of penance, allowed of by the Ordinary in your Pariſh: and whether hath your Miniſter publikely ſignified it to his Congregation, what ſummes of money have therefore beene payd, and whether have the ſayd ſummes of money, or part thereof beene diſtributed by your Miniſter, and Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens to the poore, or otherwiſe imployed to ſome ſuch godly, and charitable uſe, as was preſcribed by the Ordinary?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether do you know any houſholder, or other perſon
<pb facs="tcp:27689:6"/>whatſoever, within your Pariſh or Chappelry that is deceaſed y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> has made his laſt Will, and Teſtament, and the ſame not hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therto beene proved, nor adminiſtration taken from the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary or other Iudge competent?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether hath your Chancellor, Commiſſary, or other exerciſing Eccleſiaſticall Iuriſdiction, heard any matter of of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice privately in their Chamber, without their ſworne Regiſters, or their Deputies preſence, or in their abſence, of ſuch other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as the Law doth allow for an Actuary in ſuch a caſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Touching Schoole-maſters.</head>
               <p>FIrſt, whether have you in your Pariſh any Schoole-maſter, who teacheth either in publike Schoole or private Houſe, whether is he reputed to be of ſound Fayth, and Religion, doth he reſort duely to Church, and receive the Communion, or doth he give any evill example of life, is he allowed by the Ordinary under his hand, and ſeale: or doth your Miniſter or Curate teach, and is he allowed in like manner?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether doth your Miniſter or Schoole-maſter, who tea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheth the Catechiſme by Authority ſet forth, doth he when there is any Sermon or divine Service, bring his ſchollers to Church, &amp; ſee them quietly, and reverently ordered, doth he examine them after their returne, what they have learned of the Sermon?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether doth he at other times teach them ſuch ſentences of Holy Scripture, as may induce them to all godlineſſe, doth he teach the <hi>Grammar</hi> ſet forth by King <hi>Henry</hi> the eight, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued by King <hi>Edward</hi> the ſixt, and Queene <hi>Elizabeth?</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether hath your, Schoole-maſter an Vſher under him, are they both diligent, is your Vſher allowed by the Ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry doth your Schoole-maſter direct bis Vſher the forme, &amp; man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of teaching, and doth he weekely take account of him, and the Schollers under his charge, how they have profited, and what they have learned, and out of what Authors?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether hath eyther of them ſpoken, writ, or taught a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt any thing whereunto he formerly ſubſcribed, as the Kings Supremacy, the Articles of Religion, Booke of Common prayer, or any thing therein contained?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:27689:7"/>
               <head>Touching the Pariſh-Clarke, and Sexton.</head>
               <p>FIrſt, whether have you a Pariſh-Clarke appointed by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter, ſufficient for his place, of the age of twenty yeeres at the leaſt, is he of honeſt converſation, can he read, write, and ſing, is he diligent in his office, and ſerviceable to his Miniſter in the time of Divine Service, and otherwiſe?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether doth your Clarke not being in holy orders meddle with any thing above his office, as Churching of women, Bury<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the dead, Reading of prayers, or ſuch like?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether doth your Clarke or Sexton keepe your Church cleane, the dores ſafe locked, is any thing (by his default) loſt or ſpoyled in the Church, doth he ſuffer any untimely Ringing, or any prophane exerciſe to be committed in your Church?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether doth your Clarke or Sexton, when any is paſſing out of this life, neglect to toll a bell, having notice thereof: or y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> party being dead, doth he ſuffer any more Ringing than one ſhort peale, &amp; before his buriall one, and after the ſame another.</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether doth any of your Pariſh refuſe to pay unto the pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh Clarke or Sexton ſuch wages as are unto them due, &amp; have beene accuſtomably payd?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Touching Pariſhioners.</head>
               <p>FIrſt, whether hath any in your Pariſh ſpoken againſt, or any way impugned y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> 
                  <hi>Kings Majeſties</hi> ſupremacy in Cauſes Ec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cleſiaſticall, the Truth, and Doctrine of the Church of <hi>England,</hi> the forme of Gods worſhip contained in the booke of Common Prayer, and adminiſtration of the Sacraments?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether there be any perſon or perſons knowne or vehe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mently ſuſpected to have written, printed, or by any meanes, pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed, and diſperſed, or otherwiſe to have, or to have had in his or their uſe or keeping, any Popiſh bookes or libels, or any of thoſe ſlanderous or ſchiſmaticall, &amp; ſeditious libels, or other books, that impeach the booke of common Prayer, or the Religion, &amp; Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiaſticall government, or any other part thereof, eſtabliſhed by Law in this Realme, or doth impeach the credit or eſtate of any Eccleſiaſticall perſon or governour within the ſame?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether hath any in your Pariſh ſpoken againſt or impug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned the Articles of Religion, agreede upon in <hi>Anno. Do. 1562.</hi> the rites, and ceremonies eſtabliſhed in the Church, y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment
<pb facs="tcp:27689:7"/>by <hi>Arch-biſhops, Biſhops, Deanes, Arch-deacons,</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>thers that beare office in the ſame?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether hath any in your Pariſh ſpoken againſt or impug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned the forme of making, and conſecrating <hi>Biſhops, Prieſts,</hi> or <hi>Deacons,</hi> or have any ſeparated themſelves from the ſociety of the Congregation, and combined in a new Brother-hood or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>praved the Synods of the Church of <hi>England</hi> held by the <hi>Kings</hi> Authority?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether hath any in your Pariſh maintained or defended any ſuch Miniſters or Schoole-maſters as refuſe to ſubſcribe to the order of the Church, have they affirmed that ſuch Miniſters, and adherents may make Rules, &amp; Orders in cauſes Eccleſiaſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>call, without the <hi>Kings</hi> Authority?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether doth any in your Pariſh prophane, violate, or miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpend the <hi>Lords</hi> day, commonly called Sunday, or Holidaies appoynted in the Church of <hi>England,</hi> uſing any offenſive con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſation, or worldly labour in thoſe dayes, or any of them: or is there any that wilfully refuſe, or negligently hath abſented himſelfe from Divine Prayers on Sundayes or Holidayes?</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether doth any in your Pariſh, in y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> time of Divine Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice uſe to ſit with his hat on his head: or is there any who hath not reverently kneeled when the generall Confeſſion, Letany, and other prayers are read, &amp; which have not ſtood up at the ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the Beleefe.</p>
               <p n="8">8 Whether hath any in your Pariſh diſturbed the Service or Sermon, by walking talking, or any other way, or departed out of the Church during the Service, or Sermon, without ſome ur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent cauſe, or loytered about the Church or Church-porch?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Whether there be any in your Pariſh, man or woman, being about fifteene yeere of age, that hath not received the Holy Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion, thrice at the leaſt every yeere, &amp; namely at <hi>Eaſter</hi> laſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> or thereabouts for once: &amp; whether any abandoning his or th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>r Pariſh Church, have received the Holy Communion in any <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Pariſh Church or Chappell, or private place?</p>
               <p n="10">10 Whether hath any parent beene urged to be preſented, or ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to anſwere as Godfathers for his owne child, or hath any God father or Godmother made any other anſwer, or ſpeech than is preſcribed by the Booke, or have any bin admitted for God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fathers
<pb facs="tcp:27689:8"/>fathers or God-mothers, at Baptiſme, who have not firſt recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved the Communion?</p>
               <p n="11">11 Whether doe all Fathers, Mothers, Maſters, Miſtreſſes, come, &amp; cauſe their children, ſervants, and Apprentices to come duely to the Church, and according to the Miniſters direction to be inſtructed, and catechized, or who be they that have not obeyed the Miniſter herein?</p>
               <p n="12">12 Whether have any perſons married together within the Degrees of Conſanguinity or Affinity prohibited, ſet forth in a Table, appoynted to be placed in every Church: or have any married or contracted themſelves under the age of one, and twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty yeeres, without the conſent of their Parents, or Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours, if their parents be dead?</p>
               <p n="13">13 Whether have any perſons, once lawfully married, forſaken each other, or doe live aſunder otherwiſe than by law is per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted: or doe any, being divorced or ſeparated, marry againe the former Wife or Husband yet living?</p>
               <p n="14">14 Whether hath any of your Pariſh unreverently uſed your Miniſter, or have any layd violent Hands upon him, or diſgraced his office, and calling, by word or deede?</p>
               <p n="15">15 Whether have you in your Pariſh any Popiſh Recuſant or maintayner of popiſh doctrine, or ſuſpected to keepe or diſperſe Schiſmaticall bookes, or to favour any Hereſte or errour?</p>
               <p n="16">16 Whether have you any common reſorters to your Church which are not of your Pariſh, abandoning their owne Pariſh Church, or doe any ſuch receive the communion amongſt you: what be their names, and of what pariſhes are they?</p>
               <p n="17">17 Whether hath any upon any Sunday or Holiday opened their ſhops, exerciſed their trade, or uſed any gaming, bin in any <hi>Tavern</hi> or <hi>Ale-houſe,</hi> or otherwiſe ill imploied in the time of Divine Service?</p>
               <p>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Whether are there in your Pariſh any adulterers, fornica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>t<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rs, inceſtuous perſons, bawds, receivers of defamed perſons, cloſe favourers, conveyers away of ſuch, or which ſuffer to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part any incontinent perſon unpuniſhed, or are there in your Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh any blaſphemers, common ſwearers, drunkards, ribawds, uſurers, malicious ſlanderers, ſcolds or ſowers of diſcord, or any defamed of the ſame crune?</p>
               <p n="19">
                  <pb facs="tcp:27689:8"/> 19 Whether doe any in your Pariſh adminiſter the goods of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> dead, without authority, or ſupreſſe their Will or Teſtament: have any Executors neglected to performe their Wils, eſpecially in paying of Legacies given to the Church, to the poore, or to any other charitable or godly uſes?</p>
               <p n="20">20 Whether doe any refuſe to pay to the reparations, orna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, &amp; other things by Law required to be in your Church, as they are ſeaſed by Law: or are any dwelling out of your Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh, which hold land in your Pariſh, that refuſe the like pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment or ſeaſement?</p>
               <p n="21">21 Whether have any not being of your Pariſh beene chriſtned, churched, buried, or received the Communion, or beene married out of your Church, both parties dwelling in your Pariſh?</p>
               <p n="22">22 Whether have all women in your Pariſh delivered of child, come at convenient time after to Church, to give thanks, &amp; have they beene Churched according to the forme of the Booke of common Prayer?</p>
               <p n="23">23 Whether hath y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Perambulation of the circuit of your Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh bin obſerved once<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> every yeere, if not, by whoſe default is it?</p>
               <p n="24">24 Whether hath any in your Pariſh given the Church-war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens or Side-men or any of them evill words for doing their due<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty according to their oath, and conſcience, in making preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment for their default?</p>
               <p n="25">25 Whether there beany man or woman in your Pariſh, that uſeth witch-craft, ſorcery, charmes, or unlawfull prayer or invo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations in <hi>Latine</hi> or <hi>Engliſh,</hi> or otherwiſe upon any Chriſtian body or beaſt, or any that reſorteth to the ſame for counſell, or helpe, and what be their names?</p>
               <p n="26">26 Whether there be any, that pretending themſelves to be <hi>Phyſicians</hi> or <hi>Chirurgeons,</hi> do take upon them to practiſe <hi>Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſicke,</hi> or <hi>Chirurgery,</hi> not being lawfully licenſed thereunto, or which refuſe to ſhew their ſayd licence to<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the Miniſter, or Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate, and Church-wardens of your Church or Chappell, when they ſhall be hereunto required?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Touching Church-wardens, and Sworne-men.</head>
               <p>FIrſt, whether doe any in your Pariſh take upon them to be Church-warden or Side-man, which is not lawfully choſen by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Miniſter, &amp; Pariſhioners, according to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> 
                  <hi>Canon,</hi> or do any
<pb facs="tcp:27689:9"/>continue y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> office longer than <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ye<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>re, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> choſen a<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>gaine, or that it be a cuſtome <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den to continue two yeers, a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap> all ſuch <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>fficers yerely in <hi>Eaſter</hi> weeke?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether doe your Chu<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>-wardens with<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap>th at the moſt after their yeere <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> before the Miniſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> Pari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhio<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ers, give up a iuſt acco<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> of all ſuch money &amp; <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> they have received, &amp; beſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap>ed, have they <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> remai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning in their hands belong<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> to their Church o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>iſh, by Bill indented, to be delivere<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the next Church <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether have y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Church-<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>rdens, with the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter, from time to time p<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>ded a ſufficient quanti<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 words">
                     <desc>〈◊◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> white bread, &amp; who<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eſome w<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> for y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> number of co<gap reason="illegible" extent="5 letters">
                     <desc>•••••</desc>
                  </gap>cant<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether doe the Church-<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>rdens, and Sworn<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>me<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> before every viſitation, and at oth<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> times when there is <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap>n meete and confer about th<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> preſentments, &amp; the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap>ring of their Articles, &amp; who hath (af<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>er notice given him of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> time and place) careleſly abſented himſelfe?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether the forfeitur<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> twelue pence, for <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> from Church, appoynted by St<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap> to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> uſe of the poore, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>, and levied by the Church-war<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>, &amp; imployed according <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the ſaid Statute: and whether i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap>ſaid forfeiture taken of all perſons which ſtand wilfully ſuſp<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>d or excommunicated?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether have any Church-wardens loſt, ſold, or detained any Goods, Ornaments, Bels, Rents, or Imp<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                     <desc>…</desc>
                  </gap>ts, of the Church?</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether doe, you the Church wardenns, and S<gap reason="illegible" extent="8 letters">
                     <desc>〈8 letters〉</desc>
                  </gap>, about the middeſt of divine Service, uſually walke out y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Church, and ſee who are abroad in any-<hi>Ale-houſe,</hi> or elſewhere about, or evilly imployed, and have <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>u preſented all ſuch off<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nders to the Ordinary?</p>
               <p n="8">8 Whether doe you kno<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> or have heard a fame of any offence committed, or duty omitt<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> by any of your Pariſh before your time, &amp; heretofore not preſeared by the former Church-wardens to the Ordinary, or as yet not reformed, and have you preſented the ſame?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Finally, doe you know of any matter or cauſe which is a breach of the lawes Eccl<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>icall here not expreſſed, &amp; have you preſented the ſame?</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:27689:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
